shop.ca 2015-11-22

# Privacy

[SHOP.CA](about:blank) Network Inc. ("[SHOP.CA](about:blank)") is committed to protecting the privacy, confidentiality, security and accuracy of the personal information we collect, use and disclose. This privacy policy (the "Privacy Policy") is a statement of principles and guidelines outlining how we collect, use, disclose and protect the information we collect. [SHOP.CA](about:blank)’s privacy practices are in accordance with all applicable federal and provincial laws and regulations.

**CONSENT**

BY USING OUR SITES, YOU AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. WHENEVER YOU SUBMIT INFORMATION VIA OUR SITES, YOU CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE, AND DISCLOSURE OF THAT INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY. PLEASE BE SURE TO READ OUR ENTIRE PRIVACY POLICY BEFORE SUBMITTING INFORMATION TO OUR SITES. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you may refuse or withdraw your consent to certain parts of the identified purposes at any time by contacting us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide you, or continue to provide you, with certain services or information that may be of value to you.

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

Canadian privacy legislation defines personal information broadly as information about "an identifiable individual" or as information that allows an individual to be identified. The types of personal information that we may collect from you from time to time include: your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and birth date. In addition, from time to time, we may ask you to provide us with more detailed information regarding your interests, occupation, and background. Finally, from time to time, we may acquire demographic and other information about you (e.g. your occupation and interests) in order to serve you better.

**WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We collect your personal information to provide you with helpful, relevant information and the best shopping experience on our sites, mobile applications, third-party social media channels,and in our e-mails. In addition, from time to time, we may use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * to understand your needs and preferences, including to contact and communicate with you and to conduct surveys, research and evaluations;
  * to deposit loyalty earnings, ie Aeroplan Miles, SHOP.CA Credits
  * to administer contests run on our sites;
  * to manage and develop [SHOP.CA](about:blank)’s business and operations;
  * to meet legal and regulatory requirements;
  * to engage in business transactions, including the purchase, sale, lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal, securitization or financing involving [SHOP.CA](about:blank);
  * any other purpose we may indicate to you from time to time.

If you provide your email address and expressly consent to opt-in to receive promotional and informational emails or other commercial electronic messages, you are always given the opportunity to remove that consent via an unsubscribe request provided within email, as a change in preference in a mobile application, or by contacting our Customer Loyalty Team by telephone at 1.855.4.SHOP.CA or by postal mail at SHOP Network Inc. 70 Peter Street, Suite 200, Toronto, Ontario, M5V 2G5.

**WHAT HAPPENS TO INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE ON A CONTEST ENTRY?**

[SHOP.CA](about:blank) uses a variety of contests and similar promotions to increase awareness of our business. We generally request contact information so that we can notify you if you are a prize-winner. As well, in some cases we may contact contest entrants with product information. Contest entries generally include a way for you to indicate that you do not want to be contacted based on the information on your entry. Because contests may involve co-sponsors outside [SHOP.CA](about:blank) who have their own privacy practices, it is always advisable to read the entry form and contest rules before entering.

**TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We may disclose your personal information to our affiliates and to the following third parties in the following circumstances:

(a) Disclosure to Service Providers: We may disclose your personal information to companies or individuals that provide services on our behalf, including our loyalty partner, software developers (including website developers and hosts), data processing providers, document management providers, and office services providers. We will only provide those third parties with the information they need to deliver the service(s) contracted for and we will ensure that they enter into agreements with us to protect the personal information that they receive.

(b) Law Enforcement and Legal Disclosure: [SHOP.CA](about:blank) may disclose your personal information to a government institution that has asserted its lawful authority to obtain the information or where [SHOP.CA](about:blank) has reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity, or to comply with a subpoena or warrant or an order made by a court, person or body with jurisdiction to compel the production of information, or to comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information, or to [SHOP.CA](about:blank)’s legal counsel. If you would prefer for us NOT to share your information as described above, simply inform us (see "Contact Us" below).

**CONTROL OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At [SHOP.CA](about:blank), we want you to be able to maintain control over how we use your personal information. In particular, you always have the option to instruct us not to use your name, address, e-mail address, etc. beyond providing you with the service(s) or information you requested (see "Contact Us" below). E-mail communications will always include an identification of the sender and an "Unsubscribe" option.

**WHERE IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION STORED?**

Your personal information is stored in secured locations and on servers controlled by [SHOP.CA](about:blank), located either at our offices or at the offices of our service providers. For access to your personal information, please contact us using the contact information in the "Contact Us" section.

**HOW CAN YOU ACCESS AND CORRECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

Upon written request, subject to certain exceptions, [SHOP.CA](about:blank) will inform you of the existence, use, and disclosure of your personal information and will give you access to that information. Access requests should be sent using the contact information in the "Contact Us" section. If [SHOP.CA](about:blank) determines not to provide you access to your personal information, we will provide an explanation. Individuals may request the correction of their personal information, and [SHOP.CA](about:blank) will make the necessary correction(s).

**HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We make every reasonable effort to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of personal information under our control. Only authorized employees and suppliers have access to your personal information. [SHOP.CA](about:blank) retains your personal information only as long as necessary to fulfill the identified purpose(s) or as otherwise required or allowed by law. Also, if you send us an email message, we may retain that message and your email address, as well as any response we send you. 

**GENERAL**

For your convenience, search functions are provided on our sites. We keep logs of the words searched to learn more about what kind of information our visitors are seeking and thus improve our services. For your convenience, [SHOP.CA](about:blank)’s site(s) sometimes contain hyperlinks to websites managed by third parties. By activating these hyperlinks, you will leave our sites for those of the third parties, which may have different privacy policies and practices than [SHOP.CA](about:blank). [SHOP.CA](about:blank) cannot be held liable for the use of such third party websites. We believe that [SHOP.CA](about:blank)’s advertising does not appeal directly to children 13 years old and under. We do not knowingly direct our advertising at children under the age of 13, except as permitted by law. No personal information should be submitted to or posted on our sites by individuals under 18 years of age without the permission of a parent or guardian.

**CONTACT US**

If you have any questions, concerns or requests relating to this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [ **privacy@shop.ca**](mailto:privacy@shop.ca)

**CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**

SHOP.CA reserves the right to update, modify or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. This Privacy Policy is intended to comply with the provisions of the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (Canada) and Canada’s Anti-Spam Law (CASL). 

**TERMS OF SERVICE**

SHOP.CA controls www.shop.ca from its offices within the Province of Ontario, Canada. The Website can be accessed from all provinces and territories of Canada and from other countries around the world. As each of these jurisdictions have laws that may differ from those of the Province of Ontario, by accessing the Website, You agree that all matters relating to access to, or use of, the Website, or any other hyperlinked website, shall be governed by the laws of the Province of Ontario and the federal laws of Canada applicable therein. You also agree and hereby submit to the non-exclusive personal jurisdiction and venue of the courts of the Province of Ontario and acknowledge that You do so voluntarily and are responsible for complying with all local laws.
